Guide to the Facilities Department records, 1904-2008 RG0063
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Facilities Department records
1904-2008
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Facilities Dept.
RG0063
28 Linear Feet
Collection includes blueprints of buildings (including Lisner Hall, Lisner Auditorium, Stockton Hall, Mitchell Hall, Bradley Hall, Dorothy Betts Theater, Gelman Library), campus plans, parking lots owned, and expansion programs. There are also images of projects from the Mount Vernon Campus.
Box 8
Box 7
Box 5
Box 6
Box 1
Box 2
Box 4
Box 13
Box 14
Box 11
Box 12
Box 9
Box 10
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from the Facilities Department.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Facilities Department of The George Washington University operates and maintains University facilities and provides quality support services to improve the physical environment and the overall mission of the University in the education, research and health care delivery processes. The primary functions of Facilities Management are Life Safety, Emergency Response, Maintenance, Repairs and General Services. They are also responsible for most minor and some major construction, alterations, renovations and support for many University functions such as Graduations, Colonial Inauguration and Registration, etc. They also provide support to Architecture, Engineering & Construction (AEC) during design and or construction. This includes but is not limited to shut off of utility systems, signage, key and lock installation, and landscaping support.
Facilites was previously known as the Physical Plant.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials for this collection include blueprints of buildings (including Lisner Hall, Lisner Auditorium, Stockton Hall, Mitchell Hall, Bradley Hall, Dorothy Betts Theater, Gelman Library), campus plans, Arlie House scrapbook of photographs, parking lots owned, expansion programs, infrared energy loss survey reports. There are also photographs of projects on the Mount Vernon Campus. The material ranges in dates from 1904 to 2008. Note: Not all series are processed. Ask staff for assistance.
The Foggy Bottom Campus Plan, 2006-2025 is cataloged and available in the SCRC stacks.
Collection Organization
Organized into 11 series: Blueprints; Blueprints and plans; Brochure and plans; Mechanical drawings; Machine shop plans; Blueprints of six buildings; Airlie House scrapbook and campus plans; Infrared energy loss survey report; Blueprints and plans for campus; Departmental files, and Mount Vernon Campus construction photographs.
Dorothy Betts Marvin Theatre; Stockton Hall; Mitchell Hall; Washington (D.C.); Melvin Gelman Library; Lisner Auditorium; Photographs; Planning; Buildings; Scrapbooks; Building construction; George Washington University. Bradley Hall; George Washington University
- Blueprints, 1925-1939; RG0063 Series 1; 1 Linear foot (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of blueprints of Lisner Hall (1939), Mitchell Hall (1926), and Stockton Hall (1925). They range in date from 1925-39, and were transferred to University Archives in 1998.
  - Blueprints of Lisner Hall, Mitchell Hall, and Stockton Hall, 1925-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Lisner Hall (1939), Mitchell Hall (1926), Stockton Hall (1925)
- Blueprints and plans, 1950-1980; RG0063 Series 2; 2 Linear foot (Oversize-folder 2, Tube 1, Oversize-folder 1)
  This series consists of blueprints and plans, including Lisner Auditorium, parking lots, Building V, Student Union, Building F, Building R, Building I, Building II, Building OO, Building CC, Building RR, Binney Hall, campus plans, leased buildings, Associated General Contractors building. They range in date from 1950-80, and were transferred to University Archives in 1987, with the exception of those from the Associated General Contractors building, which were transferred to the University Archives in 2007.
  Formerly ACC#282
  - Lisner Auditorium and building "W" H St. NW, 11/17/1967 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.1)
    SQ: 79 Lots: 61 & 848
  - University Parking Lot, 2031 and 2033 H St. NW, 1970 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.2)
    SQ: 101 Lots: 43 & 819
  - University Parking Lot, 2031 and 2033 H St. NW, undated (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.3)
    SQ: 101 Lots: 821 & 822
  - University Parking Lot, 2031 & 2033 H St. NW, 1970 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.4)
  - Parking Lot, 2036 & 2038 Eye St. 823 21st St., 1970 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.5)
    SQ: 101 Lots: 840, 842, & 843
  - Parking Lot #9, H St. NW, 1975 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.6)
    SQ: 101
  - University Parking Lots, 2022 & 2030 G St. NW, 1970-1976 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.7)
    SQ: 103 Lots: 13, 17, 25, 812, 813, 815
  - Building "V" 2114 H St. NW, 1980 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.8)
    SQ: 79
  - Parking Lot, 1973 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.9)
    SQ: 103 Lots: 13, 17, 20, 25, 800, 810, 811
  - Parking Lot, 1978 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.1)
    SQ: 103 Lot: 815
  - Proposed Parking Lot, 1973 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.11)
    SQ: 250 Lot: 43
  - Parking Lot, 1355 H St. NW, 1974 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.12)
  - Planting Plans for Parking Lot, M St. & East Side of Calhoun Hall, 1974 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.13)
  - Parking Lot, 2144 Eye St. NW, 1975 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.14)
    SQ: 77 Lot: 822
  - Addition to Parking Lot #4, 2146, 2142, & 2140 Eye St. NW, undated (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.15)
    SQ: 77 Lots: 823, 824, & 860
  - Parking Lot, 821, 823, 825 22nd St. NW, 1970 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.16)
    SQ: 77 Lots: 42, 43, 44, 45, 820
  - Plat of Property, 20th, 21st, H, Eye Sts., 03/1980 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.17)
  - Plat for Building Permit, 06/1978 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.18)
    SQ: 40 Lots: 20, 33, 820, 822, 840
  - 23rd St & G NE Corner, 12/1966 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.19)
    SQ: 56; includes posted sign blueprints
  - Parking Lot, S.E. corner of SQ: 21, 10/1968 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.2)
    Lots: 800, 801, 801, 801, 804
  - Parking lot, 2007-29 F St. NW, 05/1976 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.21)
  - Parking Lot # 9, 2031 H St., 09/1975 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.22)
  - Parking Lot # 11, 923 23rd St. & 9304 New Hampshire Ave., 12/1977 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.23)
    SQ: 40 Lots: 20, 33, 820, 821, 822
  - Parking Lot C & 8, 10/1975 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.24)
    SQ: 42 Lot: 845
  - Parking Lot C, St. Mary's Court, 10/1975 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.25)
  - Emergency Phones, F & G Sts. NW, 10/1969 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.26)
  - Parking lot, 06/1968 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.27)
    SQ: 57 Lot: 21
  - Parking lot, 729-732 22nd St. NW, 06/1970 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.28)
    SQ: 79 Lots: 33, 34, 35, 36
  - Lisner Auditorium and Building W, 11/1967 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.29)
    SQ: 79 Lots: 61, 848
  - Student Union Building, 11/1948 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.3)
  - District Surveyor's Survey, 10/1950 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 1.31)
    SQ: 79 Lots: 3, 4, 60
  - Building F, 706 20th St. NW, 03/1963 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 2.1)
    SQ: 102 Lot: 838
  - Building R, 712 20th St. NW, 07/1963 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 2.2)
  - Buildings F & R, 706 & 712 20th St., 06/1975-01/1976 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 2.3)
  - Mini-Park, 22nd & Eye Sts. NW, 04/1976 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 3.1)
    SQ: 55 Lot: 853
  - 21st St. right, 06/1969 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 3.2)
    SQ: 102 & 79 (partial)
  - Parking lot, 06/1972 (Oversize-folder 1, Folder 3.3)
    SQ: 55 Lots: 23, 24
  - Parking lot, 01/1970-1973 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 1.1)
    SQ: 42 Lot: 833, 839, 841
  - Mini-Park, 2500 Eye St., 08/1980 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 1.2)
  - Parking Lot #11, 01/1978 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 1.3)
    SQ: 40
  - Parking Lot Booth, Eye St. NW, 02/1966 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 1.4)
    SQ: 41 & Lot: 832
  - Hospital Parking Lot, 906 23rd St., 09/1967-1977 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 1.5)
    SQ: 40 Lots: 823, 20, 33, 822, 821, 820
  - Building I, 2135 G St. NW, 06/1976 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 2.1)
    SQ: 79 Lot: 850
  - 2034-2026-2034 Eye St, 07/1979 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 2.2)
  - Binney Hall Building F, 2018 Eye St. NW, 07/1950-1976 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 2.3)
  - GWU Plans: Parking Lots, Buildings Owned, Real Estate Owned, 1985-1986 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.1)
  - Buildings, 07/1976 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.2)
    U 2023 H St. (rear); W 2024 G St. (rear); NN 2025 H St. (rear)
  - University Library, 2130 H St., 12/1977 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.3)
  - Leased Buildings, 827 22nd St., 1979 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.4)
  - Leased Buildings, 2008 Eye St., 1979 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.5)
  - Leased Buildings, 2124 Pa. Avenue, 11/1973 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.6)
  - Leased Buildings, 2146 Eye Street, 1973 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.7)
  - Leased Buildings, 2142 Eye Street, NW, 1971 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.8)
  - Leased Buildings, 2006 Eye Street, NW, 1979 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.9)
  - Leased Buildings, 917 22nd St. NW, 1979 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 3.1)
  - Building LL, 1908 G St. NW, 06/1975 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 4.1)
  - Building OO, 815 21st St. (rear), 08/1978 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 4.2)
  - Building S, 2025 H St. NW, 10/1976 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 4.3)
  - Parking Lot #4, 2146, 2142, & 2140 Eye St., 12/1977 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 4.4)
    SQ: 77 Lots: 860, 823, 824
  - Parking Lot #3, 2023 H & 2110 Eye St., 10/1975 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 4.5)
    SQ: 101 Lots: 21, 844, 845
  - Building CC, 2035 H St., 09/1962-1972 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 5.1)
  - Building RR, 2145 Eye St., 07/1980 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 5.2)
  - Parking Lot C, St. Mary's Court 23rd St., 10/1975 (Oversize-folder 2, Folder 5.3)
    SQ: 42 Lot: 840
  - Associated General Contractors of America National Office Building, 20th and E St. NW, 02/1957; Series 2 (Tube 1)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Transferred to the University Archives on December 4, 2007.
- Brochures, plans, 1970-1980; RG0063 Series 3; 1 Linear foot (Box 1)
  This series consists of two copies of a booklet describing new activities building (Smith Center), and 2000 Pennsylvania Avenue development plan. They range in date from 1970-80, and were transferred to University Archives in 1990.
  - One Building Builds Another, 10/1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Pamphlet concerning university's physical and academic growth
  - At Play in Colonial Fields, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Two copies of a pamphlet concerning the history and planned future development of university's sports and activities facilities
  - Planned Unit Development, 08/11/1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Application to the District of Columbia Zoning Commission for a Consolidated Planned Unit Development and Zoning Map Amendment
- Mechanical drawings, 1928-1959; RG0063 Series 4; 1 Linear foot (Box 1)
  This series consists of mechanical drawings of buildings (Lisner Hall, Corcoran Hall, Stockton Hall, hospital, Nurse's home, Adams Hall, Calhoun Hall, Everglades Hall, Madison Hall, medical school, President's House, Staughton Hall, Strong Hall, Student Union, Warwick Cancer Center, Welling Hall, Tin Tabernacle, etc.), University seal and flag, parking lots, and plats of GW land holdings. They range in date from 1928-1959, and were added to the University Archives collections from a backlog in 2003.
  - Loose material in front of binder, 02/01/1928 (Box 1, Folder 1.1)
    Plat showing holdings of GWU - Square 102 (Between G and H and 20th and 21st Streets), and adjacent buildings
  - 2100 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.2)
    5 sheets
  - 2033 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.3)
    4 sheets
  - 2027 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.4)
  - 2025 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.5)
  - Lisner Hall, 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.6)
  - 2017 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.7)
  - 2015 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.8)
  - 2009 & 2011 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.9)
  - 2022 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.1)
  - 2024 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.11)
  - 2101 G St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.12)
  - Corcoran Hall, 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.13)
  - 2024 & 2026 H St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.14)
    3 sheets
  - 2014 & 2016 H St. (Gymnasium), 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.15)
  - Stockton Hall, 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.16)
  - 714 20th St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.17)
  - 704 20th St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.18)
  - Engineering Laboratory, 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.19)
    2 sheets
  - GWU Medical School, 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.2)
    7 sheets
  - GWU Hospital, 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.21)
  - Square 87, 22nd and New York Ave., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.22)
    1 sheet
  - Square 16, 26th and K St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.23)
  - Nurses Home, Square 248, 14th and K St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.24)
  - Square 13, 26th and M St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.25)
  - Square 62, 23rd and C St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.26)
  - Square 210, 15th and Rhode Island Ave., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.27)
  - Square 209, 15th and Church St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.28)
  - Square 126, 18th and K St., 1935 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1.29)
  - Building sign - "International House", undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University Flag, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - University Seal, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Parking lots, Square 119, 19th and Penn. Ave., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Parking lots, Square 101,, 2003 H St., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Parking lots, Square 57, 626 22nd St., undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Parking lot at 2012 I Street, Square 101, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - John Quincy Adams Hall, 1900 H St., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Calhoun Hall, 2100 Eye St., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    9 sheets
  - Everglades Hall, 2223 H St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fraternity House, 2002 G St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lumber Shed, rear 2025 H St., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Madison Hall, 736 22nd St., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Medical School, 1335 H St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Medical School, 1337 H St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Medical School, 1339 H St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Paint Shop, rear 2027 H St., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - President's House, 2330 Tracy Place, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Staughton Hall, 707 22nd, St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Strong Hall, 620 21st St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Student Union, 2125 G St. and Bender Building, 2127 G St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    6 sheets
  - Warwick Cancer Clinic, 2300 K St., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Welling Hall, 814 22nd St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Shop Office, 2031 H St., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Gymnasium ("Tin Tabernacle"), 2010 H St., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Machine shop plans, 1989; RG0063 Series 5; 1 Linear foot (Oversize-folder 1)
  This series consists of Physics Department machine shop plans, and date from January 1989. They were transferred to University Archives in 1990.
- Blueprints of six buildings, 1964-1978; RG0063 Series 6; 1 Linear foot (Box 1)
  This series consists of blueprints of 2128 Penn. Avenue, 934 23rd street, 926 23rd street, 2119 F street, Building "G", and Building "Q." They range in date from 1964-78, and were transferred to University Archives in 1984.
  - 2119 F St. Plans, 02/1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 2128 Penn. Ave. Plans, 03/1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 815 21st St. Plans, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 815 21st St. Plans, 11/1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 926 23rd St. Plans, 03/1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 934 23rd St. Plans, 02/1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Building Q Plans, 12/28/1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Building Q Plans, 04/1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Building Q Plans, 09/1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Building Q Plans, 07/10/1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Airlie House scrapbook and campus plans, 1965-1987; RG0063 Series 7; 1 Linear foot (Box 1)
  This series consists of a scrapbook of Airlie House photos; real estate, buildings, and parking lots owned (campus plans) by GW. They range in date from 1965-87, and were transferred to University Archives in 1987.
  - Airlie House Scrapbook, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Folder - Expansion Program Notes, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Campus Map (Foggy Bottom) - Parking Lots Owned, 07/01/1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Campus Map (Foggy Bottom) - Real Estate Owned, 07/01/1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Campus Map (Foggy Bottom) - University Buildings, 07/01/1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Infrared energy loss survey report, 1976; RG0063 Series 8; 1 Linear foot (Map-folder 1)
  This series consists of an infrared energy loss survey report, which dates from December 1, 1976. The report was transferred to University Archives in 1987.
- Blueprints and plans for campus, 1922-1997; RG0063 Series 9; 17 Linear foot
  This series consists of blueprints and plans for campus, including dormitories, Bacon Hall, Bradley Hall, Dorothy Betts Theater, Lisner Auditorium, Harris Plan, 2000 Penn. Avenue, Square 102, Himmelfarb Library, Gelman Library, Lisner Library, buildings/property owned, parking lots. They range in date from 1922-97, and were added to the University Archives collections from a backlog in 2001.
  - 1910 and 1912 G St. Plans, 12/1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 19th and 1914 G St. Plans, Women's dorm, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 2022 G St., NW, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 2129 and 2222 Eye St., NW, 1938-1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Adams, John Quincy Hall Plans, 1957-1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Bacon Hall Plans, 20th and H St., NW, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bacon Hall Plans, 20th and H St., NW, 03/1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bacon Hall Plans, 20th and H St., NW, 1975-1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Academic Cluster (Center) Plans, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bacon Hall Plans, 20th and H St., NW - transparencies of plans, 1957-1963 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bradley (later Chapin) Hall, 1719 Eye Street, NW, 1946-1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Building DD Plans, 1944-1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Building E Plans, 2003 G St., NW, 11/1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Building H plans, corner of 19th and G Streets, NW, 07/1965 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Building TT, 753 21st Street, NW, 06/1971 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Building Z (Student Bookstore) H Street next to Lisner Auditorium, 1949-1964 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Buildings Owned, 07/1983 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Buildings, Real Estate owned, 12/1989 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Buildings, Real Estate Owned/ Parking Lots Blueprints and Plans, 1971-1974 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Buildings, Real Estate Owned/ Parking Lots Blueprints and Plans, 1975-1982 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Campus Development Plan Boundaries and Property Listing, 12/1997 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Campus Plans - Artists Concept of Campus (drawing with aerial perspective of Foggy Bottom looking north), 1950 ca. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Corcoran Hall - Equipment/Work space renovation, 12/1988 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Davis-Hodgkins House, 2140 Eye St., NW, 1969-1976 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Dorm - Renderings of Women's Dorms, Strong Hall, 1938 ca. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Dorothy Betts Marvin Theater (Marvin Center), 04/1967 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Francis Scott Key apartments - alterations, 02/1942 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - GW Hospital - Square 54 miscellaneous plans, 1944-1966 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - GW Hospital Proposed Parking Area Plans, 1965 ca. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Harris Plan for University Yard (Square 102), 1925 ca. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Preliminary Plans and Revisions, 1969 ca.-1970 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Library - Gelman Library plans, Civil, Architectural, Structural, 03/1971 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    (Folder 1)
  - Library - Gelman Library schedules for Mechanical, Plumbing, Electrical, 03/1971 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    (Folder 2)
  - Library - Gelman Library plans for Study Carrels and Furniture, 03/1971 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    (Folder 3)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Floor plans, 04/1971 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Floor plans, 04/1971 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    (2 copies with revisions)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Aluminum entrances and windows, 11/1971 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Schedule of building equipment, 12/1972 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Floor plans, 10/1972 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    (7 copies, 5 with revisions)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Book shelving layout, 01/1972 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Floor plans, 06/1972 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    (with revisions Aug/Sept, 1972)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Outside plazas and front entrance, 03/1973 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Library - Gelman Library - Floor plans, 08/1973 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Library - Gelman Library - 2nd floor revision, 03/1974 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Library - Lisner Library and Building D (Stuart Hall) plans, 11/1938 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Library - Lisner Library and Building D (Stuart Hall) plans, 11/1950-12/1950 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Library - Lisner Library and Building D (Stuart Hall) plans, 05/1951 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Library - Lisner Library and Building D (Stuart Hall) plans, 06/1951 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Lisner and Stuart Hall, 08/1976 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Lisner Auditorium blueprints, 1940-1978 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Maury Hall Plans, 702 19th Street, 05/1966 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Medical - Alterations to Medical Research building, 1339 H Street, NW, 1955-1965 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Medical - Medical School and Hospital Lab Plans, Rear 1337-38 H Street, NW (Square 25), 11/1931 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Medical School Plans - 1331, 1335, 1337 H Street, NW, 1963-1966 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Medical - Square 250, 06/1989 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Music Hall (Building FF) Plans, 2023 H St., NW, 1963-1969 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Parking Lots - 24th and H St. Parking Lot Plans, 1963-1965 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Parking Lots - Expansion Plans, Square 42, 1971-1974 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Parking Lots - Lot 8 plan, Square 42, 03/1973 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Parking Lots - Lot 11 Plans, 906 23rd St., NW, 1976 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Parking Lots - Lot 3 plan, Square 101, 09/1981 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Paul Himmelfarb Medical Library, 23rd & Eye Streets, NW, 07/1970 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Plan for the future of George Wash. University [a 3D model], 1959 January; Series 9; 1 artifact(s) 1 3D model (Object 1, Item 1)
    Henry Churchill F.A.I.A. Satterlee & Smith Architects Associates
  - Planning Materials for GW Property and Buildings, 08/1964 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Property desired for purchase by GW, 1922 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Proposed alterations of buildings to comply with DC Zoning, 09/1961 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Proposed campus development plans and real estate owned (Part of U.S. Grant III papers), 1948 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    (Donated by Washington)
  - Proposed Religious Center04/1961Historical Society, 04/2003 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Square 55 - Plot plan, 07/1980 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Square 102- Plot plans, 1966-1982 (Box 69, Folder 1)
- Departmental files, 1904-2008; RG0063 Series 10; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 3, Box 2, Box 4)
  This series includes drawings, correspondence, memorandums, statements, and programs. They range in date from 1904 to 2008. The materials concern cleanliness of buildings, room arrangement for events, testing fire alarms, classroom lighting, Recycling Department, conserving energy, policy and procedures, the Physical Plant Department, the Potomac Rose Society, Ecology Action, the University gates, proposed buildings, and the energy crisis.
  - Buildings, 1927-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Buildings - general - architectural survey of properties in Foggy Bottom, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Buildings - general - architectural survey of properties in Foggy Bottom (edited-1999) (Box 1, Folder 3)